Evan McEldowney Digital Designer & Front End Developer

evanmceldowney.com | evanmceldowney@gmail.com | (401)368-0787 | San Francisco, CA USA

Experience

UX Designer | Elevated Third

2018 - 2019 Managed the design, content, and development of 5+ client facing websites

Denver, CO Designed websites from wireframes to high fidelity for B2B & B2C websites

Developed site strategy, brand, and content architecture with clients

Created interaction prototypes for live user and client testing

Freelance Designer & Front-End Developer | Self Employed

2016 - Present Design websites and products for startups, the UN Global Compact and MIT San Francisco, CA Develop component based Javascript, SASS, and PHP Wordpress websites

Boston, MA Rebrand companies for strategic reentry into consumer markets

Guide executives on user experience and market strategy

Events Director | Scout Student Design Agency

2016 - 2017 Founded a sold out 300 person conference with speakers from Airbnb, Twitter, and

Boston, MA Monotype on the ethical role of designers in technology development

Managed an eight-person team in the production and marketing of 14 events

Developed strategic fundraising partnerships with academic and professional leaders

Developed social media and print strategies for implementation

Design Co-op | Yeti.co

Spring 2016 Designed and developed UX for mobile apps and websites

San Francisco, CA Created an educational VR application that was launched on the app store

Ran recurring weekly user testing sessions and design sprints Wrote proposals for military & academic project & product grants

Product Lead | Scout Student Design Agency

2015 Managed a three person team in producing a B2C buying and selling marketplace

Boston, MA Rebranded the company with a fresh visual & component based design system

Developed front end HTML, SASS, and Javascript for hand off to back end

Print and Interactive Designer Co-op | Studio Gusto

Spring 2015 Developed and designed custom and WordPress based web pages for clients

Perugia, Italy Wrote and researched for multiple clients' social media presence

Developed social media campaigns for a variety of international luxury clients

About Me

Hi, I am strategically minded creative dedicated to enhancing user experience, product development, and front end development in consumer-facing products. I love tackling large complex issues and combining multiple disciplines and perspectives to tell stories that elevate communication, interaction, and design.

Education

Northeastern University Interactive Media & Graphic Design 2012-2017 Boston, MA

Skills

Design

- » Product Design
- » Product Strategy
- » Wireframing
- » Branding
- » Prototyping
- » UI Design
- » Animation

Development

- » HTML
- » SASS
- » Javascript
- » PHP
- » MEAN Stack
- » Web Animation
- » Responsive WebDevelopment
- » Github

Management & Marketing

- » Project Management
- » Agile Design
- » Social Media
- » Marketing
- » Campaign Development
- » Event/Conference
- Organization

Interests

- » Ethics in Al
- » Visual Journalism
- » Futurology
- » Data Visualization
- » Policy Research